前情提要
你是谁
Who are you?
金・莫里亚蒂
Jim Moriarty.
你好
Hi!
犯罪顾问
Consulting criminal.
虽然我乐此不疲
I have loved this,
我们之间的小游戏
this little game of ours.
已经死人了
People have died.
是个人都会死
That's what people do!
我会阻止你
I will stop you.
如果你还继续追根究底
If you don't stop prying...
我会烧死你
I'll burn you.
会把你架在火上烤熟
I will burn the heart out of you.
回- 头- 见
Catch you later.
再见才怪
No, you won't!
抱歉  孩子们
Sorry, boys!
我这人就是变化无常
I'm so changeable!
这是我的缺点
It is a weakness with me,
不过平心而论
but to be fair to myself,
这是我仅有的缺点
it is my only weakness.
我不能让你再穷追不舍
You can't be allowed to continue.
不可以了
You just can't.
我也想过要说服你
I would try to convince you,
不过我要说的你都知道了吧
but everything I have to say has already crossed your mind.
或许我的回答你也同样清楚
Probably my answer has crossed yours.
"活着"  比吉斯乐队
"Stayin' Alive" by the Bee Gees
不介意我接个电话吧
Do you mind if I get that?
当然不会  请便
Oh, no, please.
你还有一辈子时间呢
You've got the rest of your life.
喂
Hello?
当然是  你想怎么样
Yes, of course it is. What do you want?
再说一遍
Say that again!
再说一遍  记住  如果你骗我
Say that again, and know that if you're lying to me,
我会抓住你  剥皮拆骨
I will find you, and I will skin you.
等着
Wait.
抱歉
Sorry.
死期未到
Wrong day to die.
是吗
Oh.
你有更好的选择了吗
Did you get a better offer?
我们会再见面  夏洛克
You'll be hearing from me, Sherlock.
如果你真有你所说的东西
So if you have what you say you have,
我可以让你发财
I will make you rich.
如果你没有
If you don't,
我就用你做人皮皮鞋
I'll make you into shoes.
怎么回事
What happened there?
有人让他改变了主意
Someone changed his mind.
问题是...
The question is...
是谁
who?
您可曾试过堕落放纵  殿下
Well, now, have you been wicked, Your Highness?
是的  阿德勒小姐
Yes, Miss Adler.
新福尔摩斯 第2季 第1集
Sherlock S02E01 720p hdtv x264
贝尔格莱维亚丑闻
华生医生的博客 5月30日
生活在继续
是时候更新消息了
我打算讲述几个我们最近处理的
小案子
蒂利
・
布里格斯
欢乐
巡游
你在写什么
What are you typing?
的
真相
一桩
- 博客  - 关于什么
- Blog.  - About?
关于
我们
Us.
熔化
笔记本
也就是说我
You mean me.
电脑
为什么
Why?
的
奇怪
案子
因为你打的内容很多
Well, you're typing a lot.
那又怎样
Right, then.
看看我们有什么新案子
So, what have we got?
- 我老婆经常工作到很晚 - 无聊
- My wife seems to be spending a very long time at the office.  - Boring.
我想我丈夫可能有外遇
I think my husband might be having an affair.
没错
Yes.
她不是我姑姑  她被人调包了
She's not my real aunt, she's been replaced.
我确定这不是她
I know she has.
- 我分辨得出人的骨灰  - 出去
- I know human ash.  - Leave.
无论您提出何种报酬  我们都能满足
We are prepared to offer any sum of money you care to mention
- 只要能找回这些文件  - 无聊
- for the recovery of these files.  - Boring.
我们建了个网站
We have this website,
用来解释漫画书的真正意义
it explains the true meaning of comic books,
因为人们忽略了其中很多主题
cos people miss a lot of the themes.
但随后所有的漫画开始变成事实
But then all the comic books started coming true.
有点意思
Oh...interesting.
华生医生的博客
极客漫画通
三个年轻人来到
贝克街
声称
极客漫画通  那是什么
Geek Interpreter, what's that?
是标题
That's the title.
标题有啥用
What does it need a title for?
漫画
故事
真有人读你的博客吗
Do people actually read your blog?
那你以为那些委托人是怎么找来的
Where do you think our clients come from?
我自己有网站
I have a website.
你在上面列举了240种不同的烟灰
In which you enumerate 240 different types of tobacco ash.
没人看你的网站
Nobody's reading your website.
这就对了  漂染金发  没有明显死因
Right then, dyed blonde hair, no obvious cause of death,
除了这些不知是啥的斑点
except for these speckles, whatever they are.
真的假的
Oh, for God's sakes!
- 干嘛  - 斑点金发女
- What?  - The Speckled Blonde?!
华生医生的博客
斑点金发女
三十来岁  漂染金发
身上覆满奇怪红斑
爷爷去世时他们不让我们去看他
They wouldn't let us see Granddad when he was dead.
是因为他去了天堂吗
Is that cos he'd gone to heaven?
人死了不会去天堂
People don't really go to heaven when they die,
他们被送到特定地点烧掉
they're taken to a special room and burned.
夏洛克
Sherlock...
昨天杜塞尔多夫[德]发生一起空难
There was a plane crash in Dusseldorf yesterday.
全员遇难
Everyone dead.
疑似遭恐怖分子炸毁
Suspected terrorist bomb.
我们也看新闻
We do watch the news.
你说着无聊就换台了
You said "Boring" and turned over.
从航班记录上发现
Well, according to the flight details,
此人已办理登机手续
this man was checked in on board.
他的大衣里有登机牌的存根
Inside his coat he's got a stub from his boarding pass,
航班上的餐巾纸
napkins from the flight,
还有航班特供饼干
even one of those special biscuits.
这是他的护照  在柏林机场盖过戳
Here's his passport, stamped at Berlin Airport.
所以这人昨天本该死在德国的空难中
So this man should have died in a plane crash in Germany yesterday,
结果却死在萨瑟克区的汽车后备箱里
but instead he's in a car boot in Southwark.
是祸躲不过
Lucky escape.
有想法吗
Any ideas?
目前有八个
Eight so far.
好吧  是四个
OK, four ideas.
也许只有两个
Maybe two ideas.
华生医生的博客
夏洛克・福尔摩斯的困惑
萨里郡荒地汽车内发现45岁男子尸体
不  不要提未解决的案子
No, no, no, don't mention the unsolved ones.
华生医生的博客
夏洛克・福尔摩斯的困惑
萨里郡荒地汽车内发现45岁男子尸体
人们想看到你凡人的一面
People want to know you're human.
为啥
Why?
因为他们感兴趣
Because they're interested.
才怪  他们为啥感兴趣
No, they're not. Why are they?
看看这个
Hmm, look at that.
- 1895  - 你说什么
- 1,895.  - Sorry, what?
我昨晚重置了访客计数
I reset that counter last night.
在过去八小时里
This blog has had nearly 2,000 hits
有将近2000人点击博客
in the last eight hours.
这就是你的生计来源  夏洛克
This is your living, Sherlock,
才不是什么240种烟灰
not 240 different types of tobacco ash.
是243种
243.
这次用什么标题
So what's this one?
肚脐谋杀案
Belly Button Murders?
肚脐疗法
The Navel Treatment?
外面有很多记者  伙计们
There's a lot of press outside, guys.
反正不是冲着我们来
Well, they won't be interested in us.
那是在你走红网络前
Yeah, that was before you were an internet phenomenon.
其中一些人特别要求拍你们的照片
A couple of them specifically wanted photographs of you two.
老天
God's sake!
约翰
John.
遮住脸  快走
Cover your face and walk fast.
这有助于营造良好公众形象
Still, it's good for the public image,
毕竟是这样的大案子
big case like this.
我是私家侦探  公众形象毫无益处
I'm a private detective, the last thing I need is a public image.
帽子侠和罗宾:网络侦探二人组
夏洛克和网络技术
夏洛克和约翰  博客控侦探
夏洛克・福尔摩斯  网络奇人
喂
Hello.
我想是时候了  你说呢
I think it's time, don't you?
天啊
Oh, dear!
手指
Thumbs!?
大门...
The door was...
小伙子们  有新客户了
Boys! You've got another one!
从头说  别让我觉得无聊
Tell us from the start, don't be boring.
14小时前
喂
Hey!
你还好吗
Are you OK?
你好
Excuse me!
你没事吧
Are you all right?
长官  您的电话
Sir, phone call for you.
我是卡特
Carter.
- 听说过夏洛克・福尔摩斯吗  - 谁
- Have you heard of Sherlock Holmes?  - Who?
你很快就会见到他
Well, you're about to meet him now.
这是你的案子  你说了算  我只是
This is your case, it's entirely up to you, this is just...
给你提个友好建议
friendly advice, but
让夏洛克在犯罪现场调查五分钟
give Sherlock five minutes on your crime scene,
他怎么说你都听着
and listen to everything that he has to say.
还有尽量...
And as far as possible...
不要揍他
try not to punch him.
好的
Ok.
长官  这位先生说
Sir, this gentleman says
- 他要跟您谈谈  - 我知道
- he needs to speak to you...  - Yes, I know.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
约翰・华生  这里能无线上网吗
John Watson. Are you set up for Wi- Fi?
你也知道这有点丢人吧
You realise this is a tiny bit humiliating?
还好  无所谓
It's OK, I'm fine.
现在
Now...
让我看看河边
show me to the stream.
我不是说丢你的人
I didn't really mean for you.
听着  这才第六起
Look, this is a six.
第七起之前我离开公寓去勘察毫无意义
There's no point in my leaving the flat for anything
我们已经达成共识了
less than a seven, we agreed.
现在往后退
Now go back,
让我看草地
show me the grass.
我们什么时候达成的共识
When did we agree that?
昨天  停
We agreed it yesterday. Stop!
- 近点  - 我昨天根本不在家
- Closer.  - I wasn't even at home yesterday.
我去了都柏林
I was in Dublin.
你没听见是你的问题
It's hardly my fault you weren't listening.
- 闭嘴  - 我不在家你还一个人叨叨
- Shut up!  - Do you just carry on talking when I'm away?
谁知道你什么时候不在家
I don't know, how often are you away?
现在
Now...
让我看看排气管回火那车
show me the car that backfired.
在那边
It's there.
就是这辆车发出巨响的吧
That's the one that made the noise, yes?
对
Yeah.
如果你在考虑枪击...
If you're thinking gunshot...
没有枪击
There wasn't one.
他没有中弹
He wasn't shot,
致命伤是
he was killed by a single
背后一处钝器重击
blow to the back from a blunt instrument,
但凶器和凶手一起神秘消失了
which then magically disappeared, along with the killer.
我看这次至少得有八起案子
It's got to be an eight, at least.
你还有两分钟
You've got two more minutes,
他们想知道更多司机的信息
they want to know more about the driver.
不用管他  他是个白痴
Oh, forget him, he's an idiot.
他怎么会认为自己是疑犯
Why else would he think himself a suspect?
是我认为他有嫌疑
I think he's a suspect.
- 把电脑递过去  - 好吧
- Pass me over.  - All right,
要是有静音按钮  我巴不得马上按掉
but there's a mute button, and I will use it.
举高点  我才不要在下面说话
Up a bit! I'm not talking from down here!
好吧  你举着  举着吧
OK. Just take it, take it.
成功谋杀且没有证人
Having successfully committed a crime without a single witness...
他何必又叫警察又找侦探
why would he call the police and consult a detective?
- 想跟你公平竞赛  - 他在耍小聪明
- Fair play?  - He's trying to be clever.
他是过于自负了
It's overconfidence.
你见过他吗
Did you see him?
过度肥胖
Morbidly obese,
口臭熏天证明是单身汉
the undisguised halitosis of a single man living on his own.
右袖子证明他沉迷于色情网站
The right sleeve of an internet porn addict,
呼吸模式证明他是未治疗的心脏病患者
the breathing pattern of an untreated heart condition.
自尊低  智商低  命不长久
Low self- esteem, tiny IQ and a limited life expectancy,
你居然认为他能策划罪案
and you think he's a criminal mastermind?!
别担心  这推论傻疯了
Don't worry, this is just stupid.
你说什么  我心脏怎么了
What did you say? Heart what?
去河边
Go to the stream.
河里有什么
What's in the stream?
- 过去看看  - 夏洛克
- Go and see.  - Sherlock!
你怎么不应门
You weren't answering your doorbell.
他的卧室在后面  去拿些衣服
His room's through the back, get him some clothes.
你们到底是什么人
Who the hell are you?
抱歉  福尔摩斯先生...
Sorry, Mr Holmes...
- 夏洛克  怎么了  - 您得跟我们走
- Sherlock, what's going on? What's happening?  - You're coming with us.
信号断了  不知怎么...
I've lost him. I don't know what...
- 华生医生  - 我是
- Dr Watson?  - Yeah.
- 找您的  - 好  谢谢
- It's for you.  - OK, thanks.
不  先生  是直升机
No, sir, the helicopter.
福尔摩斯先生  您要去的那个地方
Please, Mr Holmes, where you're going
您一定会希望着装得体
you'll want to be dressed.
西装：
700镑
无武器
修剪
整齐
坐办公室
惯用右手
室内工作
小狗
x2
x3
我很清楚我要去哪儿
I know exactly where I'm going.
- 你穿了裤子吗  - 没有  - 好吧
- You wearing any pants? - No. - OK.
我们在白金汉宫哎  很好
At Buckingham Palace. Right.
我在努力克制偷烟灰缸的冲动
Aah, aah, I am seriously fighting an impulse to steal an ashtray.
我们来这里做什么
What are we doing here,
- 夏洛克  正经回答我  - 我不知道
- Sherlock, seriously, what? - I don't know.
是来谒见女王吗
Here to see the Queen?
很显然  你说对了
Oh, apparently, yes.
拜托你们一回  别这么幼稚好吗
Just once, can you two behave like grown- ups?
我们破案  我用博客记录  他忘了穿裤子
We solve crimes, I blog about it, and he forgets his pants.
我对此不抱太大希望
I wouldn't hold out too much hope.
麦考夫  我手头还有案子
I was in the middle of a case, mycroft.
什么案子  驴友和发动机回火事件
What, the hiker and the backfire?
我过了一眼警方报告  有点平淡无奇了吧
I glanced at the police report, a bit obvious, surely?
- 显而易见  - 那就别操心了
- Transparent. - Time to move on then.
这里是白金汉宫
We are in Buckingham Palace,
整个英国的中枢之地
the very heart of the British nation.
- 夏洛克・福尔摩斯  穿上裤子  - 为啥
- Sherlock Holmes, put your trousers on! - What for?
为了客户
Your client.
我的这位客户...
And my client is...?
地位显赫  尊荣至极
Illustrious, in the extreme.
所以我必须说明  客户的名字保密
And remaining, I have to inform you, entirely anonymous.
- 麦考夫  - 哈瑞
- Mycroft. - Harry.
舍弟礼数不周  请允许我
May I just apologise for the state
- 代他道歉  - 我想是他太忙了吧
- of my little brother. - A full- time occupation, I imagine.
这位一定是约翰・华生医生
And this must be Dr John Watson,
曾在第五诺森伯兰兵团服役
formerly of the Fifth Northumberland Fusiliers?
正是  你好
Hello, yes.
- 我老板非常喜欢你的博客  - 你老板
- My employer is a tremendous fan of your blog. - Your employer?
尤其喜欢写铝拐杖的那一篇
Particularly enjoyed the one about the aluminium crutch.
谢谢
Thank you.
这位年轻的福尔摩斯先生
And Mr Holmes the Younger.
你没有照片上那么高
You look taller in your photographs.
多亏那件修身外套和这位矮个子朋友
I take the precaution of a good coat and a short friend.
麦考夫  我不接匿名客户
Mycroft, I don't do anonymous clients.
我习惯了案子一头是谜
I'm used to mystery at one end of my cases,
两头都是谜就太麻烦了  再见
both ends is too much work. Good morning.
此案事关国家  别闹了
This is a matter of national importance. Grow up!
- 松开我的床单  - 不然呢
- Get off my sheet! - Or what?
不然我就直接走出去
Or I'll just walk away.
- 那我成全你  - 两位  注意场合
- I'll let you. - Boys, please...not here.
这位客户到底是谁
Who is my client?
看看你在什么地方  然后动脑筋想想
Take a look at where you're standing, and make a deduction.
雇你的是全国最有权势的人  还要点明吗
You are to be engaged by the highest in the land, now, for God's sake!
快把衣服穿上
Put your clothes on!
我负责招呼
I'll be mother.
我从小到大就是听你招呼
And there is a whole childhood in a nutshell.
我老板遇到了棘手的问题
My employer has a problem.
这件事极其敏感  存在犯罪的可能性
A matter has come to light of an extremely delicate
如今面临曝光的危险
and potentially criminal nature,
在此紧急关头
and in this hour of need,
- 亲爱的弟弟  有人想到了你  - 为什么
- dear brother, your name has arisen. - Why?
我们有各种各样的警力
We have a police force of sorts,
还有无孔不入的军情六处
even a marginally secret service.
- 为什么来找我  - 大家都找你帮忙
- Why come to me? - People come to you for help,
对吧  福尔摩斯先生
don't they, Mr Holmes?
但名下有海军的人可没找过我
Not to date anyone with a navy.
此案关系到最高机密  以及信任问题
This is a matter of the highest security, and therefore of trust.
- 连自家的情报机关也信不过  - 当然
- You don't trust your own secret service? - Naturally not.
他们都为了钱监视别人
They all spy on people for money.
我们时间有限
I do think we have a timetable.
是的  当然了
Yes, of course. Erm...
你认识这个女人吗
What do you know about this woman?
没印象
Nothing whatsoever.
那你就要多加注意了
Then you should be paying more attention.
她去年成为两起政党丑闻的焦点
She's been at the centre of two political scandals in the last year,
最近又与某著名作家离婚
and recently ended the marriage of a prominent novelist
我送你一份礼物
因为她不仅给老公带绿帽子  还脚踏两条船
by having an affair with both participants separately.
你知道我对花边新闻不感兴趣
You know I don't concern myself with trivia.
她是谁
Who is she?
艾琳・阿德勒
Irene Adler.
业内称她为"那个女人"
Professionally known as "The Woman".
业内
Professionally?
她有很多外号  她最喜欢"施虐女王"
There are many names for what she does. She prefers "Dominatrix".
读取图片>>
- 施虐女王  - 别紧张
- Dominatrix. - Don't be alarmed.
是性方面的
It's to do with sex.
性不会让我紧张
Sex doesn't alarm me.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
她提供的是  这样说吧  愉悦的惩罚
She provides, shall we say, recreational scolding
给那些有此嗜好
for those who enjoy that sort of thing
且乐意付钱的人
and are prepared to pay for it.
这些是从她的网站下载的
These are all from her website.
我猜这位阿德勒女士有一些不能见光的照片
And I assume this Adler woman has some compromising photographs.
你反应很快  福尔摩斯先生
You're very quick, Mr Holmes.
不难推断  到底是谁的照片
Hardly a difficult deduction. Photographs of whom?
一个对我老板很重要的人
A person of significance to my employer.
希望我们不要再谈这方面的事了
We'd prefer not to say any more at this time.
你们什么都不说吗
You can't tell us anything?
我可以告诉你们  是个年轻人
I can tell you it's a young person.
一位年轻女性
A young female person.
照片有多少张
How many photographs?
很显然  数量非常大
A considerable number, apparently.
阿德勒小姐和这位年轻女性
Do Miss Adler and this young female
- 同时出现在照片里  - 是的
- person appear in these photographs together? - Yes.
我猜照片上有许多不能见光的场景
I assume in a number of compromising scenarios?
照我们的想象  这是肯定的
An imaginative range, we are assured.
约翰  你现在最好把茶杯放下
John, you might want to put that cup back in your saucer now.
- 你能帮忙吗  福尔摩斯先生  - 怎么帮
- Can you help us, Mr Holmes? - How?
愿意接这个案子吗
Will you take the case?
什么案子
What case?
立刻给钱  要多少给多少
Pay her, now and in full.
等阿德勒小姐公布照片
As Miss Adler remarks in her masthead,
你们就能领教她的厉害了
know when you are beaten.
她什么都不要
She doesn't want anything.
她联系过我们
She got in touch.
她通知我们说她有那些照片
She informed us that the photographs existed.
明确表示没打算使用这些照片
She indicated that she had no intention to use them
敲诈钱财或是别的什么
to extort either money or favour.
炫耀力量
Oh, a power play.
向大英最有权势的家族炫耀力量
A power play with the most powerful family in Britain.
不愧是施虐女王
Now that is a dominatrix.
这就很有趣了嘛  对吧
Ooh, this is getting rather fun, isn't it.
- 夏洛克  - 她在哪里
- Sherlock... - Hmm. Where is she?
她目前在伦敦  她在...
In London, currently. She's staying...
细节问题发短信给我  晚上再跟你们联系
Text me the details, I'll be in touch by the end of the day.
你确定到时候能搞到消息吗
Do you really think you'll have news by then?
不  我到时候能搞到照片
No, I think I'll have the photographs.
但愿你真像说的那么神奇
One can only hope you're as good as you seem to think.
爱狗
骑马
公立学校
早起
睡左边
不抽烟
父亲
一半威尔士血统
书迷
嗜茶
当然了  我还需要一样东西
I'll need some equipment, of course.
要什么都行  我会派人送到...
Anything you require, I'll have it sent...
- 能给我一盒火柴吗  - 你说什么
- Can I have a box of matches? - I'm sorry?
或者是打火机  都可以
Or your cigarette lighter, either will do.
- 我不抽烟  - 这我知道  但你老板抽烟
- I don't smoke. - No, I know you don't, but your employer does.
这件小事我们一直对外隐瞒着
We have kept a lot of people successfully in the dark
大多数人都不知道  福尔摩斯先生
about this little fact, Mr Holmes.
我不是大多数
I'm not the Commonwealth.
他这样算是谦虚了
And that's as modest as he gets.
很高兴见到你
Pleasure to meet you.
回见
Laters!
好吧  你怎么知道抽烟的事
OK, the smoking, how did you know?
证据就在你眼皮底下  约翰
The evidence was right under your nose, John,
你看见了  却没有注意到
as ever you see, but do not observe.
- 注意到什么  - 烟灰缸
- Observe what? - The ashtray.
凯特
Kate?
有客人来了
We're going to have a visitor.
我要花点时间准备一下
I'll need a bit of time to get ready.
要很久吗
A long time?
很久很久
Hmm...ages.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
我要上战场了  约翰
I'm going to into battle, John.
得换一身好盔甲
I need the right armour.
不好
No.
Nah.
我看很好
Works for me.
你看什么都好
Everything works on you.
计划是什么
So, what's the plan?
我们知道她的地址
We know her address.
直接按她家门铃吗
We just ring her doorbell?
没错  就在这儿停
Exactly. Just here, please.
你根本就没有换衣服
You didn't even change your clothes.
所以该添点儿颜色了
Then it's time to add a splash of colour.
到了吗
Are we here?
还有两条街  但就在这儿做吧
Two streets away, but this will do.
- 做什么  - 朝我的脸来一拳
- For what? - Punch me in the face.
什么颜色
Shade?
血红
Blood.
- 打你  - 没错  打我的脸  没听见吗
- Punch you? - Yes, punch me, in the face. Didn't you hear me?
经常听你说"揍我"  不过一般都是潜台词
I always hear "Punch me" when you speak but it's usually sub- text.
真是婆婆妈妈
Oh, for God's sakes!
谢了  这样就...
Thank you, that was...
行了  我们打完了  约翰
OK, I think we're done now, John!
你记清楚  夏洛克  我当过兵  杀过人
You want to remember, Sherlock, I was a soldier. I killed people.
- 你是军医  - 我也有心情不好的时候
- You were a doctor! - I had bad days!
你打算穿什么
What are you going to wear?
- 招牌战衣  - 幸运的家伙
- My battle dress. - Oh, lucky boy.
你好
Hello?
很抱歉打搅你
Oh, very sorry to disturb you,
刚才有人打了我
um, I've just been attacked, um,
他们好像拿走了我的钱包
um, and I think they, they took my wallet
还有手机
and, um, and my phone.
你能帮帮我吗
Um, please could you help me?
需要的话  我可以帮你报警
I can phone the police, if you want?
谢谢  请帮我报警
Thank you. Could you, please?
我就在这儿等他们来  你不介意吧
Would you mind if I just waited here, just until they come?
谢谢你  万分感谢
Thank you, thank you so much.
谢谢
Thank you. Oh.
我当时在场
I saw it all happen.
没关系  我是医生
It's OK, I'm a doctor.
- 你有急救箱吗  - 在厨房里  请便
- Have you got a first aid kit? - In the kitchen. Please.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
好可怜  听说你受伤了
Hello, sorry to hear you've been hurt.
- 凯特还没问过你的名字吧  - 抱歉  我
- I don't think Kate caught your name? - I'm so sorry, I'm...
人在大吃一惊的时候
It's always hard to remember an alias
很难想起编好的化名  对吧
when you've had a fright. Isn't it?
瞧啊
Well, there now.
我们都暴露了
We're both defrocked...
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生
..Mr Sherlock Holmes.
- 你是艾琳・阿德勒吧  - 瞧瞧这对颧骨
- Miss Adler, I presume. - Look at those cheekbones.
要是一巴掌扇过去我会割到手
I could cut myself slapping that face.
要不要我来试试
Would you like me to try?
好了  这就行了
Right, this should do it.
看来我错过了一场好戏
I've missed something, haven't I?
请坐  想喝茶的话  我叫女仆送来
Please, sit down. Or if you'd like some tea, I can call the maid.
我在宫里喝过了
I had some at the Palace.
- 我知道  - 很显然
- I know. - Clearly.
我也在宫里喝过茶了  如果有人要问的话
I had a tea too, at the Palace. If anyone's interested.
两天没换的衬衫
手动剃须
今晚有约会
没给姐姐打电话
新牙刷
夜不归宿
和史丹佛
一起
你知道伪装的最大问题吗  福尔摩斯先生
Do you know the big problem with a disguise, Mr Holmes?
无论你多么努力  总是一幅自画像
However hard you try, it's always a self- portrait.
你觉得我是头破血流的牧师
You think I'm a vicar with a bleeding face?
不  我觉得你神志不清
No, I think you're damaged,
沉溺幻想  坚持无上的权威
delusional and believe in a higher power.
而你的权威  便是你自己
In your case, it's yourself.
有人很爱惜你嘛
Hmm, and somebody loves you.
如果要我打你的脸  我也会避开鼻子和牙齿
If I had to punch that face, I'd avoid your nose and teeth, too.
哈哈  你能别这样光着身子吗
Ha- ha! Could you put something on, please?
- 拿纸巾遮一遮吧  - 怎么  你很尴尬
- Er, anything at all. A napkin? - Why? Are you feeling exposed?
我认为约翰并不知道该看哪
I don't think John knows where to look.
不会  他很清楚该看哪
No, I think he knows exactly where.
倒是你  我不敢肯定
I'm not sure about you.
我要是想看女人的裸体  就借约翰的手提
If I was to look at naked women, I'd borrow John's laptop.
- 你确实借了我的手提  - 那是没收
- You do borrow my laptop. - I confiscate it.
算了  我们还有正经事要谈
Never mind, we've got better things to talk about.
现在  坦白告诉我
Now, tell me, I need to know -
案子的经过如何
how was it done?
什么案子
What?
脑袋挨了一下的驴友  他怎么死的
The hiker with the bashed- in head - how was he killed?
我来不是为了这件事
That's not why I'm here.
当然不是  你的目标是拿走照片
No, no, no. You're here for the photographs,
但我不会让你拿到  所以不如我们随便聊聊
but that's never going to happen and as we're chatting...anyway
那个案子没有公开  你怎么知道
That story's not out. How do you know about it?
我认识一位警察  我知道他的癖好
I know one of the policemen. Well, I know what he likes.
你喜欢警察
And you...like policemen?
我喜欢侦探故事  还有侦探
I like detective stories. And detectives.
脑袋好使的人很性感
Brainy is the new sexy.
车位置
The position car...
车的位置与驴友有关系
The position of the car relative to the hiker,
还有那致命一击
that and the fact that the death blow
来自他的脑后  你知道这些就够了
was to the back of the head, that's all you need to know.
- 好吧  告诉我他怎么被杀  - 不是被杀
- OK, tell me, how was he murdered? - He wasn't.
你觉得不是凶杀吗
You don't think it was murder?
- 我知道不是  - 怎么知道
- I know it wasn't. - How?
就像我知道死者是位出色的冒险家
The same way that I know the victim was a excellent sportsman,
刚从海外旅行归来
recently returned from foreign travel
而我要找的照片就在这个房间里
and that the photographs I'm looking for are in this room.
- 好吧  可怎么知道  - 这么说还真在  谢谢
- OK, but how? - So they are in this room. Thank you.
约翰  把守房门  别让人进来
John, man the door, let no- one in.
乡村野外  只有两个男人
Two men alone in the countryside,
相隔几码远  还有一辆车
several yards apart and one car.
我以为你要开始找照片了
Oh, I... I thought you were looking for the photos now.
不  不
No, no.
找要花上好久  我能直接找到
Looking takes ages, I'm just going to find them,
不过你还算聪明  我们又有时间
but you're moderate clever and we've got a moment,
所以我们消遣一下吧
so let's pass the time.
两个人  一辆车  没有其他人了
Two men, a car, nobody else.
司机想要修好他的发动机
Driver's trying to fix his engine.
毫无进展
Getting nowhere.
而驴友正在休息  望着天空
And the hiker is taking a moment, looking at the sky.
是在看鸟吗
Watching the birds?
随时都会有事要发生  什么事
Any moment now, something is going to happen. What?
- 驴友要死了  - 不对
- The hiker is going to die. - No,
那是结果  要发生什么事
that's the result. What's going to happen?
- 我不懂  - 试着去理解吧
- I don't understand. - Oh, well try to.
- 为什么  - 因为你迎合衰人的幻想
- Why? - Because you cater to the whims of the pathetic
脱得精光只为了让人印象深刻
and take your clothes off to make an impression.
别让我无聊  开动脑筋吧  这是时下流行的性感
Stop boring me and think. It's the new sexy.
车要回火了
The car's going to backfire.
会发出很大的响声
There's going to be a loud noise.
- 那又如何  - 声音很重要
- So what? - Oh. Noises are important.
声音会告诉你一切  比如...
Noises can tell you everything. For instance...
谢谢
Thank you.
听到火警警报  母亲会向孩子的方向望去
On hearing a smoke alarm, a mother would look towards her child.
大火能暴露我们最在意的东西  真神奇
Amazing how fire exposes our priorities.
我真心希望这里面没有小孩子
I really hope you don't have a baby in here.
好了  约翰  你可以把警报关掉了
All right, John, you can turn it off now.
我说你可以关掉了
I said you can turn it off now!
稍等
Give me a minute!
多谢
Thank you.
按键的时候要记得戴手套
You should always use gloves with these things, you know.
最先按到的键上的油渍总是最重
Heaviest oil deposit is always on the first key used,
显然就是3了
that's quite clear the 3,
但这之后的按键顺序几乎看不出来
but after that, the sequence is almost impossible to read.
这样的保险箱应该是六位密码
I see it's a six digit code.
不可能是你的生日  无意冒犯
Can't be your birthday, no disrespect,
但你显然是个八零后  而8几乎没用到
but clearly you were born in the '80s and 8's barely used, so...
我现在就能告诉你密码
I'd tell you the code right now,
但其实呢  我已经告诉你了
but you know what? I already have.
开动脑筋吧
Think.
手放在脑后  跪在地上  别动
Hands behind your head, on the floor, keep it still!
抱歉  夏洛克
Sorry, Sherlock.
阿德勒小姐  跪在地上
Miss Adler, on the floor!
你不要我也跪在地上吗
Don't you want me on the floor,too?
不  先生  我要你打开保险箱
No, sir, I want you to open the safe.
美国人  有意思  你们怎么会感兴趣
American. Interesting. Why would you care?
- 先生  立刻打开保险箱  - 我不知道密码
- Sir, the safe, now, please. - I don't know the code.
我们一直在监听  她说她告诉你了
We've been listening, she said she told you.
如果你们真的在听  就会知道她没说
Well, if you've been listening, you'll know she didn't.
我想我一定漏了什么
I'm assuming I missed something.
而你这么聪明的人肯定没有漏掉  福尔摩斯先生
From your reputation, I'm assuming you didn't, Mr Holmes.
老天爷  她才是知道密码的人  问她
For God's sake, she's the one who knows the code, ask her!
确实  先生  不过她也知道
Yes, sir, she also knows the code
能自动报警  触响被盗警报的密码
that automatically calls the police and sets off the burglar alarm.
我已经学会不去信任这个女人了
I've learned not to trust this woman.
- 福尔摩斯先生不...  - 闭嘴
- Mr Holmes doesn't... - Shut up!
你再说一个字  一个字
One more word out of you, just one
我就崩得你脑浆涂墙
and I will decorate that wall with the insides of your head.
这对我来说可不是难事
That, for me, will not be a hardship.
- 亚彻先生  数到三  杀了华生医生  - 什么
- Mr Archer, at the count of three, shoot Dr Watson. - What?
我不知道密码
I don't know the code.
- 一  - 我不知道密码
- One.- I don't know the code.
- 二  - 她没告诉我  我不知道
- Two.- She didn't tell me, I don't know it!
我随时都准备相信你了
I'm prepared to believe you, any second now.
- 三  - 别  住手
- Three! - No, stop!
谢谢你  福尔摩斯先生  请打开
Thank you, Mr Holmes. Open it, please.
好戏上演
Vatican cameos!
- 有劳了  - 好的
- Do you mind? - Not at all.
他死了
He's dead.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 你观察力十分敏锐  - 观察力
- You were very observant. - Observant?
- 我受宠若惊  - 不必
- I'm flattered. - Don't be.
- 受宠若惊  - 他们还会有人赶来
- Flattered? - There'll be more of them,
他们肯定有人盯着这栋楼
they'll be keeping an eye on the building.
- 我们该报警  - 对
- We should call the police. - Yes.
- 这就来  - 天呐
- On their way. - For God's sake!
闭嘴  这样快
Oh, shut up, it's quick.
检查房子其他房间  看看他们怎么进来的
Check the rest of the house, see how they got in.
这就是囊中的珍宝了
Well, that's the knighthood in the bag.
那是我的东西
Oh, and that's mine.
手机已锁
请输入密码
我想照片都在这里了吧
All the photographs are on here, I presume?
- 我当然还有副本  - 你没有
- I have copies, of course. - No, you don't.
你肯定彻底解除了任何数据传输功能
You'll have permanently disabled any kind of uplink or connection.
如果不能证明这部电话里的内容独一无二
Unless the contents of this phone prove to be unique,
你也卖不出去
you wouldn't be able to sell them.
谁说我要卖了
Who said I'm selling?
要不他们怎么会感兴趣
Well, why would they be interested?
不管手机里有什么  显然不止是照片那么简单
Whatever's on the phone, it's clearly not just photographs.
那部摄像手机是我的身家性命  福尔摩斯先生
That camera- phone is my life, Mr Holmes.
要我给你除非我死了  它是我的护盾
I'd die before I let you take it. It's my protection.
- 夏洛克  - 现在不是了
- Sherlock! - It was.
- 一定是从这边进来的  - 显然
- Must have come in this way. - Clearly.
没事  她只是昏过去了而已
It's all right, she's just out cold.
天晓得她都习惯了
Oh, God knows she's used to that.
还有个后门  快去检查一下吧  华生医生
There's a back door. Better check it, Dr Watson.
好吧
Sure.
你很冷静
You're very calm.
你的陷阱刚刚杀了个人
Well, your booby trap did just kill a man.
不然他也会杀我
He would have killed me.
那是抢先自卫
It was self defence in advance.
那是什么  是什么
What is that?! What?
给我
Give it to me.
快给我
Now. Give it to me.
不
No.
- 给我  - 不要
- Give it to me. - Argh! No.
天呐
Oh, for goodness sake!
放手
Drop it.
我...说...放手
I...said...drop it!
谢了  亲爱的
Ah, thank you, dear.
好了  去转告那个时髦的小可爱
Now, tell that sweet little posh thing
照片放在我这儿很安全
the pictures are safe with me.
我不会用它们勒索她  只是为了保险
They're not for blackmail, just for insurance.
再说  我可能还想再见见她呢
Besides, I might want to see her again.
不不不  别这样
Oh, no no no no no no no.
很荣幸跟你交手
It's been a pleasure.
别扫兴
Don't spoil it.
我就想你这样记住我
This is how I want you to remember me,
记住我是打败了你的女人
the woman who beat you.
晚安  夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生
Goodnight, Mr Sherlock Holmes.
- 天呐  你做了什么  - 他会睡上几个小时
- Jesus! What are you doing? - He'll sleep for a few hours.
别让他被自己的呕吐物呛死了
Make sure he doesn't choke on his own vomit,
要不尸体会很难看
it makes for a very unattractive corpse.
这是怎么了  你给他下了什么  夏洛克
What's this? What have you given him? Sherlock?
他会没事的
He'll be fine.
我在很多朋友身上都用过
I've used it on loads of my friends.
夏洛克  能听见我说话吗
Sherlock, can you hear me?
要知道  我想错了他
You know, I was wrong about him.
他确实知道该往哪看
He did know where to look.
看什么  你在说什么
For what? What are you talking about?
我保险箱的密码
The key- code to my safe.
是什么
What was it?
我该告诉他吗
Shall I tell him?
是我的三围
My measurements.
懂了
Got it!
别说话  别起来  我来说
Oh, ssh ssh no, don't get up, I'll do the talking.
车就要回火了  而驴友
So, the car's about to backfire and the hiker,
他正盯着天空看
he's staring at the sky.
你说他可能是在看鸟  但并非如此  是不是
Now, you said he could be watching birds, but he wasn't, was he?
他是在看另一种飞行物
He was watching another kind of flying thing.
汽车回火  驴友回过头去看
The car backfires and the hiker turns to look...
而这正是他犯的大错
..Which was his big mistake.
等司机抬头看的时候
By the time the driver looks up,
驴友已经死了  他没看到杀死他的东西
the hiker is already dead. What he doesn't see is what killed him
因为那东西已经被水冲到下游了
because it's already being washed downstream.
一位经验丰富的冒险家
An accomplished sportsman
刚从海外旅行归来  还带了个...
recently returned from foreign travel with...
飞去来器回来
a boomerang.
你看一眼就明白了
You got that from one look?
绝对是时下流行的性感
Definitely the new sexy.
我...
I...
别说话了
Hush, now.
没事的
It's OK.
我只是来还你的大衣
I'm only returning your coat.
约翰
John?
John!
- 你没事吧  - 我怎么回来的
- You OK? - How did I get here?
我想你大概记不得了
I don't suppose you remember much,
你一直在胡言乱语
you weren't making a lot of sense.
我该提醒你一声
Oh, I should warn you,
我想雷斯垂德用手机把你拍下来了
I think Lestrade filmed you on his phone.
- 她在哪  - 谁在哪
- Where is she? - Where's who?
- 那个女人  就是那个女人  - 什么女人
- The woman, that woman. - What woman?
- 那个女人  就是那一位  - 艾琳・阿德勒吗
- The Woman! The Woman, woman! - Oh, Irene Adler?
她跑了  没人看见她
She got away, no- one saw her.
她不在这儿  夏洛克
She wasn't here, Sherlock.
你在干什么  别别别  回到床上去
What are you? What? No, no, no. No. Back to bed.
你早上就会没事了  睡吧
You'll be fine in the morning. Just sleep.
我当然会没事  我就是没事  绝对没事
Of course I'll be fine, I am fine. I'm absolutely fine.
是啊  你好得不得了
Yes, you're great.
你需要我的话  我就在隔壁
Now, I'll be next door if you need me.
- 我为什么会需要你  - 不为什么
- Why would I need you? - No reason at all.
下次再见
福尔摩斯先生
照片很安全
The photographs are perfectly safe.
在一个在逃的性工作者手上叫安全
In the hands of a fugitive sex worker?
她并不想勒索谁
She's not interested in blackmail.
她只想...得到保护  不知是为何
She wants...protection, for some reason.
我想你应该退出警方
I take it you've stood down the police investigation
对她家枪击案的调查了吧
into the shooting at her house?
她手里有照片
How can we do anything while
我们又能做什么  我们无能为力
she has the photographs? Our hands are tied.
她肯定喜欢你的措辞
She'd applaud your choice of words.
你看出这是怎么回事了吗
Do you see how this works?
那部摄像手机是她的免牢金牌
That camera- phone is her get out of jail free card.
你们得放过她  像对待皇室那样对她  麦考夫
You have to leave her alone. Treat her like royalty, Mycroft.
可别像她对待皇室那样对她
Though not the way she treats royalty.
那是什么
What was that?
短信
Text.
可那声音是什么
But what was that noise?
你知道还有其他人在盯着她吗  麦考夫
Did you know there were other people after her too, Mycroft,
早上好
福尔摩斯先生
你派我和约翰去之前就知道吗
before you sent John and I in there?
好像是中情局的职业杀手
CIA trained killers, I think.
- 他们真不赖  - 是啊  多谢了  麦考夫
- Excellent gangs. - Yeah, thanks for that, Mycroft.
真不知羞
It's a disgrace,
把你弟弟派去那种龙潭虎穴
sending your little brother into danger like that.
你终究只有家人能依靠  麦考夫・福尔摩斯
Family is all we have in the end, Mycroft Holmes!
- 闭嘴吧  赫德森太太  - 麦考夫
- Oh, shut up, Mrs Hudson! - Mycroft!!
抱歉
Apologies.
- 谢谢  - 不过你确实该闭嘴了
- Thank you. - Though do in fact shut up.
这声音不太好吧
Oh, it's a bit rude, that noise, isn't it?
感觉好些了吗
你做不了什么
There's nothing you can do
她也不会做什么  至少依我看是如此
and nothing she will do, as far as I can see.
我可以给她设置最高监控级别
I can put maximum surveillance on her.
何必  你盯着推特就能跟踪她的行程
Why bother? You can follow her on Twitter.
我想她的用户名是"登顶女王"
I believe her user name is The Whip Hand.
是啊  真有趣
Yes. Most amusing.
失陪  喂
Excuse me. Hello?
你的手机为什么会发出那种声音
Why does your phone make that noise?
什么声音
What noise?
就是它刚刚发出的那种声音
That noise, the one it just made.
那是短信的铃音  意味着我收到短信了
It's a text alert, means I've got a text.
你的短信一般不会叫床
Your texts don't usually make that noise.
有人拿了我的手机  显然开了个玩笑
Well, somebody got hold of the phone and apparently as a joke,
把短信铃音个性化了
personalised their text alert noise.
那么说你每次收到短信就会...
Hmm, so every time they text you...
看来如此
It would seem so.
你能把手机声音关掉吗  要是我那个年代...
Could you turn that phone down a bit? At my time of life it's...
既然你没问起
我也很好
我在想谁会拿到你的手机
See I'm wondering who could have got hold of your phone.
手机是在你的大衣里  对不对
It would've been in your coat, wouldn't it?
我不打扰你推理了
I'll leave you to your deductions.
要知道  我可不傻
I'm not stupid, you know.
你怎么得出的这个结论
Where do you get that idea?
施行邦德航空计划  已经决定了
Bond Air is go, that's decided.
跟考文垂那边核实一下
Check with the Coventry lot.
回头再谈
Talk later.
她还有什么
What else does she have?
艾琳・阿德勒  美国人不会为了几张敏感照片
Irene Adler. The Americans wouldn't be interested in her
而对她感兴趣
for a couple of compromising photographs.
她还有东西
There's more.
有很多
Much more.
有大事要发生了吧
Something big's coming, isn't it?
艾琳・阿德勒已经与你无关了
Irene Adler is no longer any concern of yours.
从现在起  你不要再插手此事
From now on, you will stay out of this.
- 是吗  - 是的  夏洛克
- Oh, will I? - Yes, Sherlock.
正是如此
You will.
可以的话  恕我失陪
Now if you'll excuse me,
我得去向我多年的老朋友负荆请罪
I have a long and arduous apology to make to a very old friend.
记得代我向她问好
Do give her my love.
拉得太好了  夏洛克  太动听了
Lovely, Sherlock. That was lovely.
- 余音绕梁啊  - 对  太棒了
- Hmm, marvellous. - Yes, very good.
要是戴上圣诞鹿角就更完美了
I wish you could have worn the antlers.
赫德森太太  有些事总要留点想象才完美
Some things are best left to the imagination, Mrs Hudson.
赫德森太太
Mrs Hudson?
- 不用了  谢了  莎拉  - 别理他  他老记错人名
- No thank you, Sarah. - Er, no, no, he's not good with names.
等等  我能记起来
No, I can get this.
莎拉是那个医生  之后换了一脸痘痘的妹子
Sarah was the doctor, then there was the one with the spots,
再之后是一身香味的那个
then the one with the nose and then,
那个闷蛋老师之后是谁来着
who was after the boring teacher?
- 没了  - 你是珍妮特  稍微排除下就出来了
- Nobody. - Jeanette! Ah, process of elimination.
天啊
Oh, dear Lord.
大家好  抱歉来晚了
Hello, everyone. Sorry, hello.
门上写着说直接上来就行了
It said on the door to just come up.
- 茉莉  你好  - 茉莉  你好
- Hello, Molly. - Hello, Molly!
每来一个  就打一次招呼  好一个礼仪之邦
Everybody saying hello to each other, how wonderful!
让我帮你...我的天啊
Let me, er... Holy Mary!
那我们现在要喝圣诞特饮了吗
So we're having Christmas drinkies then?
显然  你要喝  没人拦你
No stopping them, apparently.
一年里头只有今天
It's the one day of the year
这些小鬼会好好地陪陪我
where the boys have to be nice to me,
所以也算值了
so it's almost worth it.
- 约翰  - 啥
- John? - Hmm?
你的博客还是只有1895次点击
The counter on your blog still says 1895.
怎么会  让人圣诞节都没心思过
Oh, no, Christmas is cancelled.
你竟然放了我戴帽子的那张照片
And you've got a photograph of me wearing that hat!
- 大家都爱这张  - 才怪  说谁呢
- People like it. - No, they don't. What people?
- 髋关节怎样了  - 糟透了  谢谢关心
- How's the hip? - Oh, it's atrocious, but thanks for asking.
我见过更糟的  不过之后给我解剖了
I've seen much worse, but then I do post- mortems.
- 瞧我说的  抱歉  - 别说笑话  茉莉
- Oh, God, sorry. - Don't make jokes, Molly.
- 知道  抱歉  - 给你
- No, sorry. - Here you are.
谢谢  没想到你也在
Thank you. I wasn't expecting to see you.
我以为你会在多塞特郡过圣诞
I thought you were in Dorset for Christmas?
今天一大早
The first thing in the morning,
我就和太太重归于好了
me and the wife, back together, sorted.
瞎说  她跟一位体育老师上床了
No, she's sleeping with a PE teacher.
- 约翰  我听说你要去你姐姐家吧  - 对
- And John, I hear you're off to your sister's? Is that right? - Yeah.
夏洛克抱怨过  错  是说过
Sherlock was complaining. Saying.
有史以来她头一回洗心革面  决定戒酒
First time ever, she's cleaned up her act, off the booze.
- 才怪  - 闭嘴  夏洛克
- Nope. - Shut up, Sherlock!
看来你找了个新男友  茉莉
I see you've got a new boyfriend, Molly.
- 你对他很认真啊  - 你说什么
- You're serious about him. - Sorry, what?
- 你准备今晚见他  送他礼物  - 消停一天行吗
- You're seeing him tonight, giving him a gift. - Take a day off.
- 住口  喝你的酒  - 你们别扫兴
- Shut up. Have a drink. - Oh, come on.
你们肯定也看到袋子最上面那份礼物了
Surely you all see the present on the top of the bag.
包装精美  还系着蝴蝶结  其余的包装马虎
Perfectly wrapped with a bow. The others are slapdash.
绝对是给特别的人
It's for someone special.
红色包装纸和口红颜色一致
The shade of red echoes her lipstick,
也许是无意挑的
either an unconscious association,
也许是有意用它暗示对方
or one she's deliberately trying to encourage.
不管怎样  霍普小姐坠入爱河了
Either way, Miss Hooper has love on her mind.
显然她非常在乎他
That she's serious about him
从她送给他的礼物可见一斑
is clear from the fact she's giving him a gift at all.
显然这表明她对这段关系渴望已久
That suggests long- time hopes asolutely for long.
从她的妆容和打扮
That she's seeing him tonight
可见她今晚一定会去见他
is evident from her make- up and what she is wearing.
显然是想弥补自己嘴唇和胸部的不丰满
Obviously trying to compensate for the size of her mouth and breasts.
致最亲爱的夏洛克
茉莉敬上
你总是这样出口伤人
You always say such horrible things.
每次都是  一而再  再而三
Every time. Always. Always.
对不起  原谅我
I am sorry. Forgive me.
圣诞快乐  茉莉・霍普
Merry Christmas, Molly Hooper.
别误会  那不是我...
Oh, no! That wasn't, I didn't...
- 不是你  是我  - 我的天啊  真的假的
- No, it was me. - My God, really?
- 什么  - 是我的手机
- What? - My phone.
- 第57条  - 你说什么
- Fifty seven? - Sorry, what?
据我所知  那人已经发了57条短信了
Fifty seven of those texts, the ones I've heard.
看壁炉架
原来你一直有在数啊
Thrilling that you've been counting.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
夏洛克  怎么了
What's up, Sherlock?
- 我说了  失陪一下  - 你就不回复一下吗
- I said excuse me. - Do you ever reply?
哇  千年一遇呀
Oh, dear Lord,
该不会是打来祝我圣诞快乐的吧
we're not going to have Christmas phone calls now, are we?
难道我们国家颁布新政策了吗
Have they passed a new law?
我想你们今晚就得去找艾琳・阿德勒
I think you're going to find Irene Adler tonight.
我们早就掌握她的行踪了
We already know where she is.
虽然你好意提点  可惜这都跟你没关系了
As you were kind enough to point out, it hardly matters.
不  我意思是  你得去找她的尸体
No, I mean you're going to find her dead.
- 你还好吧  - 很好
- You OK? - Yes.
圣巴塞洛缪医院
只有这具尸体符合描述
The only one who fitted the description.
于是把她转来这边  你的第二个家
Had her brought here, your home from home.
茉莉  你没必要也过来
You didn't need to come in, Molly.
没关系  大家都忙着过...圣诞
It's OK, everyone else is busy with... Christmas.
她有点毁容了
The face is a bit sort of bashed- up,
可能有点难以辨认
so it might be a bit difficult.
- 是她本人吧  - 给我看看身体
- That's her, isn't it? - Show me the rest of her.
是她没错
That's her.
谢谢  霍普小姐
Thank you, Miss Hooper.
她是谁
Who is she?
夏洛克为什么光凭身体就认出了她
How did Sherlock recognise her from... not her face?
- 只此一根  - 为什么
- Just the one. - Why?
圣诞快乐嘛
Merry Christmas.
室内抽烟  不是违反了某条...
Smoking indoors, isn't there one of those...
某条法律吗
one of those law things?
这里是停尸房
We're in a morgue.
抽烟也害不了几个人
There's only so much damage you can do.
你怎么知道她死了
How did you know she was dead?
她有一样东西
She had an item in her possession,
她说过下半辈子都靠它了
one she said her life depended on.
- 如今却拱手相让  - 这样东西在哪
- She chose to give it up. - Where is this item now?
你看看他们
Look at them.
投入这么深的感情
They all care so much.
你有没有想过咱俩也许有毛病
Do you ever wonder if there's something wrong with us?
生命都会终结  徒留一颗破碎的心
All lives end, all hearts are broken.
爱毫无用处  夏洛克
Caring is not an advantage, Sherlock.
这是低焦油香烟
This is low tar.
你都不怎么了解她
Well, you barely knew her.
麦考夫  圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Mycroft.
新年快乐
And a happy new year.
他走了  你有没有什么发现
He's on his way. Have you found anything?
- 没有  他有抽烟吗  - 有
- No. Did he take the cigarette? - Yes.
我擦
Shit!
- 他还有十分钟就到  - 卧室里没有发现
- He's coming, ten minutes. - There's nothing in the bedroom.
看来他没藏烟  有可疑的地方我们都翻过了
It looks like he's clean, we've tried all the usual places.
你确定今晚会有危险吗
Are you sure tonight's a danger night?
不确定  不过我向来如此
No, but then I never am.
约翰  你一定要陪着他
You have to stay with him, John.
我今晚有别的事
I've got plans.
推了
No.
麦考夫
Mycroft?
真是非常抱歉
I am really sorry.
- 我那些朋友完全看错你了  - 咦
- You know my friends are so wrong about you. - Hmm?
你是个很棒的男朋友
You're a great boyfriend.
嗯  那就好
OK, that's good.
我一向觉得自己不错
I always thought I was great.
所以说夏洛克・福尔摩斯太幸运了
Sherlock Holmes is a very lucky man.
珍妮特  别这样
Oh, Jeanette, please.
我是说真的  太感人了
No, I mean it. It's heart- warming.
你愿意为他做任何事
You'll do anything for him.
而他甚至搞混你的女朋友
And he can't even tell your girlfriends apart!
我也愿意为你做任何事
I'll do anything for you,
你尽管开口  我一定做到  告诉我
just tell me what it is I'm not doing. Tell me!
我不想和夏洛克・福尔摩斯抢男朋友
Don't make me compete with Sherlock Holmes!
我可以帮你遛狗
I'll walk your dog for you.
我说到做到  我会帮你遛狗
There, I've said it, I'll even walk your dog.
- 我根本没养狗  - 哦对  那是前任女友
- I don't have a dog! - No, because that was the last one.
- 抱歉  - 真是难以置信
- OK. - Jesus!
- 再联系  - 免了
- I'll call you. - No!
好吧
Ok.
看来你俩真的没戏了吧
That really wasn't very good, was it?
回来了呀
Oh, hi.
你没事吧
You OK?
希望你这回没搞乱我的股票指数研究
I hope you didn't mess up my stock index this time!
曲子很美  夏洛克  以前没听你拉过
Lovely tune, Sherlock, haven't heard that one before.
在作曲吗
Composing?
有助于思考
Helps me to think.
你在想些什么呢
What are you thinking about?
你博客上的点击还是只有1895次
The count on your blog is still stuck at 1895.
对  出故障了  似乎修不好
Yes. Faulty, can't seem to fix it.
是出故障  还是说博客被黑了  这个数字别有用意
Faulty, or you've been hacked and it's a message.
手机已锁
密码：
■
密码错误
还有三次机会
是出故障了
Just faulty.
好的
Right.
好了
我要出去一会儿
Well, I'm going out for a bit.
那个  他有没有过什么女朋友
Listen, has he ever had any kind of girlfriend,
男朋友或走得近的人
boyfriend, a relationship, ever?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我们怎么会不知道
How can we not know?
他可是夏洛克啊
He's Sherlock.
聪明古怪如他  谁能看透他的想法
How will we ever know what goes on in that funny old head?
说的也是  回见
Right. See you.
- 约翰  - 在  你好
- John? - Yeah? Hello?
- 你好  - 今晚打算怎么过新年
- Hello. - So, any plans for new year tonight?
呃  没什么打算
Um, er... nothing fixed.
没什么非做不可的事
Nothing I couldn't heartlessly abandon.
- 你有什么提议  - 有一个
- You have any ideas? - One.
其实  麦考夫只要给我个电话
You know, Mycroft could just phone me,
他就不能别每次都搞得这么神经兮兮
if he didn't have this bloody stupid power complex.
我们就不能找间咖啡厅聊吗
Couldn't we just go to a cafe?
夏洛克也不是一直跟着我
Sherlock doesn't follow me everywhere.
请往那边走
Through there.
他马上就到
He's on his way.
你说对了  他以为是麦考夫找他
You were right, he thinks it's Mycroft.
他在谱一首苦情曲
He's writing sad music.
不吃东西  几乎不说话
Doesn't eat, barely talks,
偶尔给电视里的节目纠下错
only to correct the television.
依我看  他是真伤心了  但他可是夏洛克
I'd say he was heart- broken, but, er, well he's Sherlock.
反正伤人心的事他也没少干
He does all that anyway.
你好  华生医生
Hello, Dr Watson.
告诉他你还活着
Tell him you're alive.
那他不会放过我
He'd come after me.
如果你不告诉他  我也不会放过你
I'll come after you if you don't.
无庸置疑
Hmm, I believe you.
你的尸体在停尸台上
You were dead on a slab.
那绝对是你
It was definitely you.
DNA测试结果跟你们手上的资料一致
DNA tests are only as good as the records you keep.
- 那你肯定认识管资料的人  - 我知道他的癖好
- And I bet you know the record keeper. - I know what he likes.
而我则需要人间蒸发
And I needed to disappear.
那为什么还来找我  而我还不想见你
Then how come I can see you and I don't even want to?
听着  我犯了个错误
Look, I made a mistake,
我寄了样东西给夏洛克保管  现在我得要回来
I sent something to Sherlock for safekeeping, now I need it back.
- 所以想请你帮忙  - 不行
- So I need your help. - No.
我是为了他的安全着想
It's for his own safety.
我这么做也是  跟他说你还活着
So is this. Tell him you're alive.
- 我做不到  - 行  那我来说
- I can't. - Fine, I'll tell him
还有  我不会帮你
and I still won't help you.
我能说什么呢
What do I say?
那你平常都说什么了  你给他发了许多短信
What do you normally say?! You've texted him a lot!
- 只是聊聊罢了  - 你跟他能有什么可聊
- Just the usual stuff. - There is no usual in this case.
早上好  我喜欢你那顶滑稽的帽子
"Good morning. I like your funny hat.
我今晚不高兴  一起吃晚饭吧
"I'm sad tonight, let's have dinner.
你在《绳之于法》里的样子真性感  一起吃晚饭吧
"Hmm, you look sexy on Crimewatch, let's have dinner.
《绳之于法》是英国广播公司一档电视节目
我不饿
"I'm not hungry.
一起吃晚饭吧
"Let's have dinner".
- 你跟夏洛克・福尔摩斯调情  - 单方面  他从没回过
- You flirted with Sherlock Holmes? - At him. He never replies.
不可能  夏洛克每条短信都回
No, Sherlock always replies to everything.
人称"妙语连珠大师"
He's Mr Punchline.
他就是憋着一口气不死都要说赢对方
He will outlive God trying to have the last word.
所以对他而言我很特别吗
Does that make me special?
- 我不知道  也许是的  - 你吃醋了
- I don't know, maybe. - Are you jealous?
- 我们又不是一对  - 你们就是
- We're not a couple. - Yes, you are.
我发了  我没死
There, "I'm not dead.
我们一起吃饭吧
"Let's have dinner".
其实又有谁真正了解夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Who the hell knows about Sherlock Holmes?
以免这世上仍有人在乎  我还是声明一下
But for the record, if anyone out there still cares,
我可不是同性恋
I'm not actually gay.
可我是  看看咱们俩
Well, I am. Look at us both.
不会是我想的那样吧  你觉得呢
I don't think so, do you?
住手
Stop it!
夏洛克
Sherlock!
- 夏洛克  - 赫德森太太  别哭哭啼啼了
- Oh, Sherlock, Sherlock... - Don't snivel, Mrs Hudson,
再哭  他也不会心软收起枪
it'll do nothing to impede the flight of a bullet.
否则那该是个多么柔情的世界啊
What a tender world that would be.
救救我  夏洛克
Oh, please, Sherlock...
我想你手上有我们想要的东西  福尔摩斯先生
I believe that you have something that we want, Mr Holmes.
那你为什么不问我要
Then why don't you ask for it?
我问过这位了  不过她看来啥都不晓得
Oh, I've been asking this one, she doesn't seem to know anything.
但你心里清楚我要什么  对吧  福尔摩斯先生
But you know what I'm asking for, don't you, Mr Holmes?
颈动脉
颅骨
眼睛
动脉
肋骨
肺部
我当然清楚
I believe I do.
求你救救我
Please, help.
先把你的手下打发走
First get rid of your boys.
- 为什么  - 我不喜欢以一敌三
- Why? - I dislike being outnumbered,
不然这间屋子里的蠢货就太多了
it makes for too much stupid in the room.
- 你们两个回车里  - 然后开车走人
- You two, go to the car. - Then get into the car and drive away.
别想骗我  你知道我是谁  这可没用
Don't try to trick me, you know who I am, it doesn't work.
然后别再用枪指着我
Next, you can stop pointing that gun at me.
好让你用枪指着我吗
So you can point a gun at me?
我没枪
I'm unarmed.
- 能让我搜下吗  - 快来搜
- Mind if I check? - Oh, I insist.
白痴
Moron.
- 谢谢  - 你没事了
- Oh, thank you. - You're all right now, you're all right.
犯罪现场
务必打扰
怎么了
What's going on?
卧槽  这究竟是怎么了
Jeez, what the hell is happening?
赫德森太太被个美国人打了
Mrs Hudson has been attacked by an American,
我是在声张正义
I'm restoring balance to the universe.
赫德森太太  老天啊  你没事吧
Mrs Hudson, my God, are you all right?
他们对你做了什么
Jesus, what have they done to you?
我真是太蠢了
Oh, I'm just being so silly.
把她带到楼下去  照看好她
Take her downstairs and look after her.
没事了  我来给你看看
It's all right, I'll have a look at that.
我没事
I'm fine, I'm fine.
你到底要不要告诉我是怎么回事
Are you going to tell me what's going on?
当然了  快去
I expect so, now go.
雷斯垂德
Lestrade?
有人非法闯入我们在贝克街的公寓
We've had a break- in at Baker Street.
把你手下最不讨人厌的警官派来  再叫辆救护车
Send your least irritating officers and an ambulance.
不不不  我们没事
Oh, no, no, no, we're fine.
是那个闯入者  他把自己弄伤了
No, it's the burglar, he's got himself rather badly injured.
断了几根肋骨  脑震荡
Oh, a few broken ribs, fractured skull,
还可能伤了肺
suspected punctured lung...
他从窗子摔下去了
He fell out of a window.
真疼
Oh, it stings.
摔在了我的垃圾桶上
Oh, that was right on my bins.
他到底摔下来了几次
And exactly how many times did he fall out the window?
我记不清了  警长大人
It's all a bit of a blur, Detective Inspector.
没数
I lost count.
她今晚得睡在楼上我们房间
She'll have to sleep upstairs in our flat tonight,
我们得照顾她
we need to look after her.
- 不  - 她没事
- No... - She's fine. -
不  她有事  看看她
No, she's not, look at her.
她得搬离贝克街几天
She's got to take some time away from Baker Street.
她可以去她姐姐家住  这是医嘱
She can stay with her sister, doctor's orders.
- 别傻了  - 老天爷  她受惊了
- Don't be absurd. - She's in shock, for God's sake,
都是因为那天煞的摄像手机  手机到底在哪啊
and all over some stupid camera- phone - where is it anyway?
我知道的最安全的地方
Safest place I know.
你把手机放在你第二好的
You left it in the pocket
睡衣袍子口袋里了  你个呆子
of your second best dressing gown, you clot!
他们以为我被吓哭的时候  我想办法拿了出来
I managed to sneak it out when they thought I was having a cry.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真丢脸  约翰・华生
Shame on you, John Watson.
- 我咋丢脸了  - 赫德森太太怎么能离开贝克街
- Shame on me? - Mrs Hudson leave Baker Street?
不然英国可要沦陷了
England would fall.
手机现在又在哪
Where is it now?
没人会找的地方
Where no- one will look.
不管那手机上有什么  肯定不只是照片
Whatever's on that phone is more than just pictures.
没错
Yes, it is.
这么说她还活着
So, she's alive then.
你对此感觉如何
How are we feeling about that?
新年快乐  约翰
Happy New Year, John.
你觉得你会再见到她吗
Do you think you'll be seeing her again?
新年快乐
夏・福
- 那是手机吗  - 是部摄像手机
- Is that a phone? - It's a camera- phone.
- 你在扫描手机吗  - 是的
- And you're x- raying it? - Yes, I am.
- 那是谁的手机  - 一个女人的
- Whose phone is it? - A woman's.
是你女朋友吗
Your girlfriend?
我扫描她的东西就代表她是我女友了吗
She's my girlfriend because I'm x- raying her possessions?
- 我们都会做傻事  - 那是
- Well, we all do silly things! - Yes...
真的是这样吧
..They do, don't they?
很傻
Very silly.
她把手机送到我公寓的地址
She sent this to my address.
手机已锁
密码：
■
- 她就是爱玩游戏  - 是吗
- She loves to play games. - She does?
B
密码错误
还有两次机会
夏洛克
Hey, Sherlock...
我们有了个客户
We have a client.
啥  在你卧室里吗
What, in your bedroom?
那  谁在追杀你
So, who's after you?
- 想要杀我的人  - 是什么人
- People who want to kill me. - Who's that?
杀手呗
Killers.
你说得再具体一点也无妨
It would help if you were a tiny bit more specific.
这么说你假造了你的死
So you faked your own death
就是为了摆脱他们吗  - 成功了一阵子
to get ahead of them? - It worked for a while.
但接着你告诉了约翰  也就是告诉了我
Except you let John know you're alive, therefore me.
我知道你会替我保密
I knew you'd keep my secret.
但你不行
You couldn't.
但你确实没说出去吧
But you did, didn't you?
我的摄像手机呢
Where's my camera- phone?
不在这
It's not here.
我们又不蠢
We're not stupid.
你们拿它做了什么
What have you done with it?
如果他们认为手机在你手上  肯定会监视你
If they've guessed you got it, they'll be watching you.
那他们会以为我几个月前
Then they'll know I took a safety deposit box
在斯特兰德找了个保险储存箱
at a bank on the Strand a few months ago.
我需要那部手机
I need it.
我们不能就这么过去拿吧
Well, we can't just go and get it, can we?
茉莉・霍普  她能把手机拿到巴茨医院
Molly Hooper, she could collect it, take it to Barts.
再让某个替你跑腿的流浪汉
Then one of your homeless
带到楼下的咖啡厅里
network could bring it here, leave it in the cafe,
让咖啡厅里的招待再把手机拿上来
one of the boys downstairs could bring it up the back.
好极了  约翰  计划得好  能想到的都想到了
Very good, John, excellent plan, full of intelligent precautions.
谢谢  所以我这就去打电话给...
Thank you. So, why don't I phone...
这里面你都藏了什么
So, what do you keep on here?
我是说大致上
In general, I mean?
照片  情报  所有我觉得有用的东西
Pictures, information, anything I might find useful.
- 为了敲诈吗  - 是为了保护自己
- For blackmail? - For protection.
我一个人闯天下  难免有不得当的地方
I make my way in the world, I misbehave.
我得保证在我需要的时候
I like to know people will
别人能为我提供帮助
be on my side exactly when I need them to be.
那你是怎么搞来的这些情报
So how do you acquire this information?
我也说了  我的行为不得当
I told you - I misbehave.
但你得到了比能保护自己
But you've acquired something more
- 更危险的情报  你知道是什么吗  - 知道
- danger than protection. Do you know what it is? - Yes...
但我搞不懂
..But I don't understand it.
我想也是  让我看看
I assumed. Show me.
密码
The passcode.
密码没用
It's not working.
当然  因为这只是我做的复制品
No, because it's a duplicate I had made
好让我知道你输入了什么密码  是1058
into which you just entered the numbers 1058.
我本以为你会选择
I assumed you'd choose something
更有意义的密码  不过还是谢了
more specific than that, but thanks, anyway.
手机已锁
密码：
■
手机已锁
密码：
密码错误
还有一次机会
我也说过那部手机是我的生命
I told you that camera- phone was my life.
是不是真的我一摸就知道
I know when it's in my hand.
你真厉害
Oh, you're rather good.
你也不赖
You're not so bad.
哈米什
Hamish.
约翰・哈米什・华生不错  作为孩子名字的话
John Hamish Watson, just if you were looking for baby names.
有个男人  一个国防部的官员  我知道他的癖好
There was a man, an MOD official and I knew what he liked.
他就是喜欢炫耀
One of the things he liked was showing off.
他告诉我说  这封邮件可以拯救世界
He told me this email was going to save the world.
他不知道我拍了下来
He didn't know it but I photographed it.
他当时有点脱不开身
He was a bit tied up at the time.
屏幕上看有点小  你能看清楚吗
It's a bit small on that screen, can you read it?
007确认位置
- 能  - 显然是密码
- Yes. - Code, obviously.
我让英国最厉害的解码专家看了看
I had one of the country's best cryptographers take a look,
他也被搞得一头雾水
though he was mostly upside down, as I recall.
解不开
Couldn't figure it out.
你有办法吗  福尔摩斯先生
What can you do, Mr Holmes?
来吧  露一手给姑娘看看
Go on, impress a girl.
还有一点没想明白
There's a margin for error,
但我肯定是架波音747
but I'm pretty sure there's a 747
明天六点半将于西斯罗机场起飞  飞往巴尔的摩
leaving Heathrow tomorrow at 6.30 for Baltimore.
显然这条信息能拯救世界  但我不确定怎么个救法
Apparently it's going to save the world, I'm not sure how,
但等我一会  我才想了八秒钟
but give me a moment, I've only been on the case eight seconds.
得了  这不是密码  是飞机上的座位
Oh, come on, it's not code, these are seats on a jet.
看  没有字母I  因为会和数字1搞混
Look, no 'I' because it can be mistaken for one.
没有K以后的字母  因为飞机就这么宽
No letters past 'K' - the width of the plane is the limit.
数字总是不按顺序排列
The numbers always appear not in sequence,
但字母则几乎没有乱过顺序
but the letters have little runs of sequence all over the place.
家人和夫妻都坐在一起
Families and couples sitting together.
只有巨型喷气式飞机的座椅才会排到K
Only a Jumbo's wide enough for a letter 'K'
还有55排  所以机顶上还有一层
or rows past 55, so there's always an upstairs.
有13排说明不是那些迷信的航空公司
A row 13 eliminates superstitious airlines.
航班号的组合规律  007  又能排除一些信息
The style of the flight number, '007', eliminates a few more.
考虑到最初的情报来源
Assuming a British point
可以推断航班从英国起飞
of origin because of the original source,
加上迫在眉睫的危机  唯一符合所有条件
and assuming the crisis is imminent, the only flight that matches
并且在本周起飞的飞机
all the criteria and departs within the week is the
就是六点半从伦敦到巴尔的摩的飞机
6.30 to Baltimore tomorrow from Heathrow.
别急着要赞扬我
Please don't feel obliged to tell me that was amazing,
约翰已经这么干过了
John's expressed that in
他用光了所有表示赞扬的词语
every possible variant available in English.
我真想在这个书桌上要了你
I would have you right here, on this desk,
要到你求饶  还是两次
until you begged for mercy twice.
约翰  你能否查下航班表  看看我说得对不对
John, can you check those flight schedules, see if I'm right?
在查了
I'm on it, yeah.
我这辈子都没求过绕
I've never begged for mercy in my life.
你这次要求饶  还是两次
Twice.
嗯  你说得没错  007号航班
Yeah, you're right, flight double 'o' seven.
- 你说什么  - 你说得没错
- What did you say? - You're right.
不  你之后说了什么
No, what did you say after that?
007  007号航班
Double 'o' seven, flight double 'o' seven.
007  007
Double 'o' seven, double 'o' seven...
007有什么含义
Something, double 'o' seven...
是什么
What?
波音
明天
晚上
六点半
西斯罗
机场
波音 747 明天晚上 六点半 西斯罗 机场
007  是什么
Double 'o' seven, double 'o' seven, what?
到底是什么
What, something, what?!
施行邦德航空计划
Bond Air is go.
喷气式
飞机
向你
问好
亲爱
的
福尔摩斯
先生
喷气式飞机 向你 问好 亲爱 的 福尔摩斯先生
喷气式飞机  向你问好  亲爱的福尔摩斯先生
施行邦德航空计划  已经决定了
'Bond Air is go, that's decided.
跟考文垂那边核实一下
'Check with the Coventry lot.'
- 考文垂  - 我从没去过
- Coventry. - I've never been.
那里怎么样
Is it nice?
约翰呢
Where's John?
他出去了  出去了几小时了
He went out, a couple of hours ago.
我就是在和他说话
I was just talking to him.
他说了你会这样
He said you do that.
考文垂和这又有什么关系
What's Coventry got to do with anything?
这只是个说法  不知是真是假
It's a story, probably not true -
在二战期间
in the Second World War,
盟军知道考文垂会被德军轰炸
the allies knew Coventry was going to get bombed,
因为他们破解了德军的密码机
because they'd broken the German code,
但他们不想让德国知道他们破了密码
but didn't want the Germans to know that they've broken the code.
所以他们就任其被轰炸了
so they let it happen anyway.
你有和谁亲密接触过吗
Have you ever had anyone?
你说什么
I'm sorry?
我说的接触可是下流含义哦
And when I say had, I'm being indelicate.
- 我不懂  - 那我婉转点吧
- I don't understand. - I'll be delicate then.
- 一起吃晚饭吧  - 为什么
- Let's have dinner. - Why?
- 你饿了吧  - 不饿  - 很好
- You might be hungry. - I'm not. - Good.
我为什么想要吃晚饭
Why would I...want to have dinner...
既然我不饿
..If I wasn't hungry?
福尔摩斯先生  如果这是世界末日
Mr Holmes, if it was the end of the world,
如果这是毁灭前的最后一晚
if this was the very last night...
你会和我一起吃晚饭吗
..Would you have dinner with me?
夏洛克
Sherlock?
太迟了
Too late.
这不是世界末日  而是赫德森太太
That's not the end of the world, that's Mrs Hudson.
夏洛克  有个男人来了
Sherlock, this man was at the door,
门铃不会坏了吧
is the bell still not working?
他打坏了
He shot it.
你又是来带走我的吗
Have you come to take me away again?
- 是的  福尔摩斯先生  - 那我拒绝
- Yes, Mr Holmes. - Well, I decline.
我觉得你不会拒绝
I don't think you do.
飞机的座椅上会有一枚炸弹
There's going to be a bomb on a passenger jet.
英国人和美国人都知道这一点
The British and Americans know about it,
但为了不暴露他们的情报来源
but rather than expose their source
他们决定任其发生  飞机会爆炸
they're going to let it happen - the plane will blow up.
考文垂事件的重演
Coventry all over again.
时过境迁  烂事依然
The wheel turns, nothing is ever new.
你看上去好多了
Well, you're looking all better.
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
比如想冲你脑袋来上一枪吗  先生
Like putting a bullet in your brain, sir.
我要是这么干了  他们会赏我一枚奖章
They'd pin a medal on me if I did...
先生
..Sir.
考文垂难题
The Coventry conundrum.
你觉得我的解决方法如何
What do you think of my solution?
死者航班
The flight of the dead.
飞机在半空中爆炸  恐怖分子达到了目的
Plane blows up midair, mission accomplished for the terrorists,
伤亡数上百  但没人死亡
hundreds of casualties, but nobody dies.
很干净吧  你觉得呢
Neat, don't you think?
其实你很早就接触到事情的真相了
You've been stumbling around the fringes of this one for ages.
还是说你觉得太无聊  而忽略了其中的规律
Or were you too bored to notice the pattern?
爷爷去世时他们不让我们去看他
They wouldn't let us see Granddad when he was dead.
她不是我姑姑  我分辨得出人的骨灰
She's not my real aunt - I know human ash.
我们之前和德国人有过类似的合作
We ran a similar project with the Germans a while back,
而其中一位乘客没有赶上飞机
though I believe one of our passengers didn't make the flight.
就是你的那件案子的死者
But that's the deceased for you...
无论如何  太迟了
..late, in every sense of the word.
飞机要怎么飞
How is the plane going to fly?
当然了  无人驾驶  老把戏了
Oh, of course, unmanned aircraft, hardly new.
它不会起飞
It doesn't fly.
永远不会
It will never fly.
整个计划都取消了
This entire project is cancelled.
恐怖组织得知了我们知道炸弹的事
The terrorist cells have been informed that we know about the bomb.
现在骗不了他们了
We can't fool them now.
我们输得一败涂地
We've lost everything.
一封邮件中的一小段话
One fragment of one email,
成年累月的计划  结束了
and months and years of planning - finished.
- 你国防部的手下  - 老鼠屎坏了一锅粥
- Your MOD man. - That's all it takes.
一个孤独幼稚的男人  总想显摆自己
One lonely, naive man, desperate to show off,
和一个聪明到让他自以为很特别的女人
and a woman clever enough to make him feel special.
你们国防部选人时应该更谨慎点
You should screen your defence people more carefully.
我没在说那个国防部的人
I'm not talking about the MOD man,
夏洛克  我说的是你
Sherlock, I'm talking about you!
身陷困境的少女
The damsel in distress.
到头来  你的观察力还这么敏锐吗
In the end, are you really so obvious?
因为这不是明摆着的吗
Because this was textbook.
爱的承诺  失去的痛苦  挽回的快乐
The promise of love, the pain of loss, the joy of redemption.
然后再给他个谜题  看他尽情发挥
Then give him a puzzle and watch him dance.
别胡说了
Don't be absurd!
胡说
Absurd?
帮她破解那封邮件你用了多久
How quickly did you decipher that email for her?
一分钟吗
Was it the full minute?
还是你就这么想表现一下
Or were you really eager to impress?
我看不到5秒钟
I think it was less than five seconds.
是我让你着了她的道
I drove you into her path.
抱歉  我真没想到
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
福尔摩斯先生  看来我们得谈谈
Mr Holmes, I think we need to talk.
我也觉得  还有很多事我不太清楚
So do I, there are a number of aspects I'm still not clear on.
不是你  小阿福  没你的事了
Not you, Junior, you're done now.
还有很多  非常多
There's more, loads more.
这手机里存着秘密  照片
On this phone I've got secrets, pictures
还有能让你一败涂地的丑闻
and scandals that could topple your whole world.
你无法想象我能造成多大的破坏
You have no idea how much havoc I can cause
你也不知道如何阻止我
and exactly one way to stop me.
除非你想告诉你的上司
Unless you want to tell your masters
你最大的安全漏洞就是你弟弟
that your biggest security leak is your own little brother.
我们可以找人破解你的手机
We have people who can get into this.
我早就试过了
I tested that theory for you.
我给了夏洛克・福尔摩斯六个月时间
I let Sherlock Holmes try it for six months.
亲爱的夏洛克
Sherlock, dear, tell him
告诉他你扫描我手机时发现了什么
what you found when you x- rayed my camera phone.
手机壳下面装了四个零件
There are four additional units wired inside the casing,
我猜是含酸物质或微型炸药
I suspect containing acid or a small amount of explosive.
如果有人试图打开手机壳  硬盘就会销毁
Any attempt to open the casing will burn the hard drive.
是炸药
Explosive.
更符合我性格
It's more me.
有些数据是可恢复的
Some data is always recoverable.
你可以试试
Take that risk.
解锁需要密码
You have a passcode to open this.
很遗憾地告诉你
I deeply regret to say,
我们可以把密码逼问出来
we have people who can extract it from you.
- 夏洛克  - 有两组密码
- Sherlock? - There will be two passcodes -
一个可以解锁  一个会烧掉驱动
one to open the phone, one to burn the drive.
就算威胁她  也不知道她给的是哪一个
Even under duress, you can't know which one she's giving you
- 而机会只有一次  - 他真是厉害
- and there would be no point in second attempt. - He's good, isn't he?
我真该好好调教他
I should have him on a leash.
值得一试
In fact, I might.
那我们就毁了它  谁也别想得到里面的信息
We destroy this, then. No- one has the information.
行  好注意
Fine, good idea.
不过你要毁掉的这信息
Unless there are lives of British citizens
可是这关系着英国人民的生死
depending on the information you burn.
- 是嘛  - 告诉你是为你好
- Are there? - Telling you would be playing fair.
我不想再玩游戏了
I'm not playing any more.
这是我的要求
A list of my requests,
还要对我进行绝对安全的保护措施
find some ideas about my protection once they're granted.
要说这花不了国家多少钱
I'd say it wouldn't blow much of a hole in the wealth of a nation,
那是假的
but then I'd be lying.
你可能需要时间考虑一下
I imagine you'd like to sleep on it.
谢谢  没错
Thank you, yes.
真可惜
Too bad.
你可以去着手办这件事了
Off you pop and talk to people.
你考虑得十分周道
You've been very...thorough.
我们的人能有你一半能耐就好了
I wish our lot were half as good as you.
并不是全靠我自己  有人帮我
I can't take all the credit, I had a bit of help.
金・莫里亚蒂向你们问好
Jim Moriarty sends his love.
是  他就没消停过
Yes, he's been in touch.
迫不及待想让我盯上他
Seems desperate for my attention,
那我就满足他
which I'm sure can be arranged.
信息一直在我手上  但我不知道怎么办
I had all this stuff and never knew what to do with it.
多谢这个犯罪顾问
Thank God for the consultant criminal.
给了我很多建议
Gave me a lot of advice
教我如何跟你们打交道
about how to play the Holmes boys.
知道他叫你们什么吗
Do you know what he calls you?
冰人
The Ice Man...
和处子
..and the Virgin.
他不要任何回报  我想他只是喜欢捣乱
Didn't even ask for anything, I think he just likes to cause trouble
我要的就是这种男人
now that's my kind of man.
所以成全了你
And here you are,
让全国为之屈服的施虐女王
the dominatrix who brought a nation to its knees.
干得漂亮
Nicely played.
不
No.
什么
Sorry?
我说不
I said no.
差点成功  不过没戏
Very, very close, but no.
你太入迷了
You got carried away.
但你的游戏玩过了  你过于沉迷了
The game was too elaborate, you were enjoying yourself too much.
可没有"过头"这一说
There's no such thing as too much.
你可以享受追捕的兴奋感
Oh, enjoying the thrill of the chase is fine.
渴望用这游戏作为消遣  我完全赞同
Craving the distraction of the game, I sympathise entirely,
可你太感情用事
but sentiment?
感情用事是失败者的生理缺陷
Sentiment is a chemical defect found in the losing side.
感情用事  你说什么呢
Sentiment? What are you talking about?
你
You.
老天
Oh, dear God.
看看这个小可怜
Look at the poor man.
你不会真觉得我对你有兴趣吧
You don't actually think I was interested in you?
为什么
Why?
因为你是伟大的夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Because you're the great Sherlock Holmes,
戴着滑稽帽子的大侦探
the clever detective in the funny hat?
不
No.
因为我摸到了你的脉搏
Because I took your pulse.
脉搏加快
Elevated.
瞳孔放大
Your pupils dilated.
我猜约翰・华生觉得我不解风情
I imagine John Watson thinks love's a mystery to me,
但两人碰出火花非常简单  而且十分致命
but the chemistry is incredibly simple and very destructive.
我们初次见面时你说
When we first met, you told me that
伪装是一幅自画像  一点没错
disguise is always a self- portrait - how true of you.
保险柜的密码是你的三围
the combination to your safe, your measurements -
但这个  这个就私人多了
but this, this is far more intimate,
这是你的心  而你不应该随心而为
this is your heart and you should never let it rule your head.
如果你随便选组数字做密码
You could have chosen any random number
今天你就能顺利从这里离开
and walked out of here today with everything you work for.
但你就是忍不住  对吧
But you just couldn't resist it, could you?
我一直认为爱是个危险的不利因素
I've always assumed that love is a dangerous disadvantage.
感谢你最终又证明了这一点
Thank you for the final proof.
我所说的一切都是假的
Everything I said, it's not real.
我只是在玩游戏而已
I was just playing the game.
我知道
I know.
而你输了
And this is just losing.
手机已锁
密码：
S
■
H
E
■
R
[整句话双关]
给你  老哥
There you are, brother,
菜单
文档
图片
秘密
声音
希望里面的内容足以弥补
hope the contents make up for any inconvenience
今晚我给你造成的任何麻烦
I may have caused you tonight.
- 肯定可以  - 你要是好心  就把她关起来
- I'm certain they will. - If you're feeling kind, lock her up,
放她走的话  没了手机她肯定活不长
otherwise let her go and I doubt she'll survive long without her pretection.
- 你是要我求你吗  - 对
- Are you expecting me to beg? - Yes.
求你
Please.
你说得对
You're right.
我肯定活不过半年
I won't even last six months.
晚饭的事情抱歉了
Sorry about dinner.
你不抽烟
You don't smoke.
我也从不来咖啡馆
I also don't frequent cafes.
这是艾琳・阿德勒的档案
This the file on Irene Adler?
永久封档
Closed forever.
我正要去通知我弟弟
I am about to go and inform my brother -
或者你愿意的话  由你去说
or, if you prefer, you are -
她在美国申请到了
that she somehow got herself
证人保护计划
into a witness protection scheme in America.
新名字  新身份
New name, new identity.
她会健康地活着
She will survive and thrive...
但是他永远见不到她了
..but he will never see her again.
他会在意么
Why would he care?
最后是他摒弃了她
He despised her at the end.
提起她都不说名字  只是说"那个女人"
Won't even mention her by name, just 'The Woman'.
那是厌恶还是赞扬
Is that loathing or a salute?
独一无二  唯一让他在意的女人
One of a kind, the one woman who matters.
他不是那种人
He's not like that.
我觉得他不会有这种感觉
He doesn't feel things that way, I don't think.
我弟弟的大脑堪比科学家或哲学家
My brother has the brain of a scientist or a philosopher,
可他选择当名侦探
yet he elects to be a detective.
关于他的内心  我们能推论多少
What might we deduce about his heart?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
Neither do I.
但他最初的愿望是当一名海盗
But, initially, he wanted to be a pirate.
他应该可以接受
He'll be OK with this -
证人保护计划  再也不能见面  他不会有事
witness protection, never seeing her again - he'll be fine.
我同意
I agree.
所以我决定这样告诉他
That's why I decided to tell him that.
那事实是什么
Instead of what?
她死了
She's dead.
两个月前  她被卡拉奇的一个恐怖组织俘获
She was captured by a terrorist cell in Karachi two months ago
被砍头了
and beheaded.
确定是她本人吗
It was definitely her?
她耍过一次诈
She's done this before.
这次我保证万无一失
I was thorough this time.
想骗我得夏洛克・福尔摩斯亲自出马
It would take Sherlock Holmes to fool me,
可我觉得他并不在场  对吧
and I don't think he was on hand, do you?
所以
So...
我们怎么对夏洛克说
what shall we tell Sherlock?
看来你有消息要告诉我
Clearly you've got news.
如果是利兹三连环杀人案的话  凶手是园丁
If it's about the Leeds triple murder, it was the gardener.
- 就没人注意到耳环么  - 好啊
- Nobody notice the earring? - Hi.
不  是关于艾琳・阿德勒的事
Er no, it's, um...it's about Irene Adler.
怎么了
Well?
出事了吗  她回来了
Something happened? Has she come back?
没  她...
No, she's...
我在楼下遇到麦考夫了  他要去接个电话
I just bumped into Mycroft downstairs, he had to take a call.
她回伦敦了吗
Is she back in London?
没
No...
她...
She's, er...
- 她在美国  - 美国
- She's in America. - America?
看来她申请到了证人保护计划
Got herself on a witness protection scheme, apparently.
不知道她怎么办到  但是...
Don't know how she swung it, but...
你懂的
well, you know.
- 懂什么  - 你不能再见她了
- I know what? - You won't be able to see her again.
- 我为什么想再见她  - 我也没这么说
- Why would I want to see her again? - Didn't say you did.
- 这是她的档案吗  - 是
- Is that her file? - Yes,
我正要拿去还给麦考夫
I was going to take it back to Mycroft.
- 你想要...  - 不要
- Do you want to... - No.
那个  其实...
Listen, actually...
把她的手机给我
But I will have the camera- phone though.
- 里面没东西了  都被删掉了  - 我知道
- There's nothing on it anymore, it's been stripped... - I know, but I...
但我还是想要
..I'll still have it.
我得把它还给麦考夫  你不能留着
I've got to give this back to Mycroft, you can't keep it.
夏洛克  我得把它还给麦考夫
Sherlock, I have to give this to Mycroft,
这是政府财产了
it's the government's now...
拜托了
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我得把东西还回去了  - 好
- Well, I'd better take this back. - Yes.
在那之后  她有再给你发过短信吗
Did she ever text you again, after all that?
几个月前有一次
Once, a few months ago.
说了什么
What did she say?
再见  福尔摩斯先生
"Goodbye, Mr Holmes."
发信人  那个女人:
我不饿  一起吃晚饭吧
在宾馆好无聊  你过来吧
一起吃晚饭
约翰的博客好好笑
我看他比我更喜欢你
一起吃晚饭吧
我房间能看到塔桥和月亮
推理出我在哪
过来找我
今天我在街上看见你了
你没看见我
你知道那帽子很适合你吧
我的天呀  一起吃晚饭吧
我喜欢你那顶滑稽的帽子
我在埃及  和个白痴说话
正要上飞机
一起吃晚饭吧
你在电视上真性感
就算是你也得吃饭  一起吃晚饭吧
快看BBC1台  太搞笑了
我想给你寄个圣诞礼物
壁炉台
我没死  一起吃晚饭吧
回复:
新年快乐
再见  福尔摩斯先生
发送
听我口令
When I say run...
快跑
..run!
那个女人
The woman.
特别的女人
新福尔摩斯 第2季 第1集
Sherlock S02E01 720p hdtv x264
YYeTs人人影视